Rami M. Abdul-Aziz.

Iraq, Baghdad

Email: eng.rami1980@yahoo.com

Mobile: 07901336650

# **Objectives**

 An active Civil and Planning Engineer with 12 years experience in construction field.....I'm looking for a job that develop my professional experience to join a reputable organization that will meet my expectations to gain experience, and eventually get promoted in the organization structure to the level that I deserve and meet my ambition.

## **Education**

• B.Sc. in civil engineering from Almustanseria University in 2004, Baghdad, Iraq.

## **Experience**

• Company: Dhifaf Al-Rafideen (Iraq)

Job or Role: planning and coordinator engineer

**Projects:** Construction projects under the supervision of UNDP staff members such

as (Tikrit Hospital, Falluja iron bridge)

Year: 2018

• Company: Abraj Al-Yaqut (Iraq)
Job or Role: planning engineer

**Projects:** Iraqi Computers and Informatics Organization Building, Student Housing Baghdad University Building, Rehabilitation of Expressway No.1 R7 Nasiria – Rumaila

Year: Nov.2013-2017

• Company: Dhifaf Al-Rafideen (Iraq)

Job or Role: planning and coordinator engineer

Projects: (additional 6-classrooms & students toilet blocks) for 14 schools under the

supervision of the management of the World Bank projects in Baghdad

Year: Jun.2011-Sep.2013

• Company: Hassan Al-Muaainy (Sultanate of Oman)

Job or Role: Site engineer

Projects: Diwan Al-Amir Hotel building (ground floor + 5 typ.)

Year: 2010

• Company: Rukn Al-Safa for engineering consultancy(Iraq)

Job or Role: Quality control engineer Projects: treatment plant for heavy water

**Year:** 2009

• **Company**: Al-Shahbaa (UAE-Ajman)

Job or Role: Site engineer

**Projects:** 4 villas and 2 buildings (ground floor + 4 typ.)

**Year:** 2007

• Company: non

**Job or Role:** contractor, Site engineer

**Projects:** houses (build up, maintenance and restoration)( Iraq)

Year: 2005-2006

#### **Courses**

- Primavera-1<sup>st</sup> level (ETC-Jordan course attainment certificate).
- Primavera-advanced level (ETC-Jordan course attainment certificate).
- Quantity surveying (ETC-Jordan course attendance certificate).
- Risk management (3Ways academy-Egypt certification preparation course).
- PMP (3Ways academy-Egypt certification preparation course).
- Microsoft Excel (Training course).
- (Construction Projects) Control & Scheduling course (Training course).

#### **Skills**

## **Engineering Skills:**

- Projects management ( Planning & scheduling using primavera p6 )
- Arraying work breakdown structure
- Human resources management for project and work on the crews and motivate Construction progress.
- Make strategic program development and implementation.
- Analyze problems and the work of response required to solve it.
- Project risk management, analyze it and preparation plan risk response.
- Cost management and cash flow of projects.

- Time management and schedule, follow up and its impact on project.
- Implement construction works as per approved drawings and method of statement.
- Work management and coordination between departments.
- Follow up scope of work of project and its impact on project management plan.
- Preparation & organization documents & invoices that relating to the works in projects.
- Good knowledge in Quantity surveying of projects

### **Computer & Internet Skills:**

- Excellent in using (PRIMAVERA P6)
- Excellent in using Microsoft office applications (Excel, Word, Power point).
- Excellent in using the internet and web applications (In 2008 I worked in management of internet center in Baghdad).
- Knowledge about operating systems (windows).
- Knowledge in using Auto Cad

## **Languages Skills:**

• Arabic: Native language.

• English: Good Reading, Writing and Speaking.

#### **Personal Information**

Date of birth: 8th June, 1980 Baghdad.

Gender: Male.
Religion: Muslim.
Nationality: Iraqi.

## Social memberships:

Member in Iraqi Engineers Union.

### Reference:

• Furnished promptly upon request with supporting documents